Guide to the Stanford University Print Collection SC1039
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Prints
  - Hoover House: 5 prints from The Architect [journal], January 1931, P299; printed illustration (Box A4)
    hoover house
  - For Regina [homage to Regina Casper by Gerhard Casper on his departure from University Presidency], 2000; P300 (Box C5)
    Contents: Final print with image; Sheet with text but no image; Assorted production materials
    Casper, Gerhard.
  - Class A Membership Certificate The Professional Golfers' Association of America...C. E. Bud Finger 1970, P301; printed (Box A4)
    glued to a mat
    Finger, C. E. "Bud" Finger; Finger, Charles Edmund
  - Envelope with image of Stanford Mausoleum in upper left corner; addressed to Miss Mabel Gilson, postmarked Sept, 10, 1903, P302; envelope (Box A4)
    Mausoleum
  - Caricature drawings once part of the Beta Theta Pi scrapbook, 1930s; unclear if subjects were fraternity members or public figures. Most signed "Ward," possibly Leonard Harry Ward, class of 1933., circa 1930; P303; ink drawings (Box A4)
    Beta Theta Pi; Ward
  - Santa Fe Wing No. 9. Stanford University Centennial edition print of Oliveira painting, signed by Oliveira in 1990. [Artwork is dated 1987, but print was signed in 1990.] Mounted on foam core from earlier framing. Print format includes text from Oliveira., P304; print; 30 x 26 inches (Box MC)
    Once hung in SpecColl reading room when it was in Green East 351.
    Oliveira, Nathan
  - Stanford University [Front View Memorial Church], pen & ink drawing on watercolor paper, signed Fermin Rocker., P305; ink wash on paper; 22 x 15 in (Box C6)
    formerly framed and in museum collection as 00-284
    Rocker, Fermin
  - The Albert M. Bender Room, Reading and Administrative Center for the Division of Special Collections: Calligraphy re collections and regulations in Bender Room., P306; ink on paper; 51 x 32 cm. (Box C6)
    formerly in SUA Museum collection as 00-324
    Warren W. Ferris
  - Sanford, Fernando - pencil sketch by Peter Van Valkenburgh, February 1928; pasted on board, P307; pencil (charcoal?) on paper; 14 x 22 inches (Box C6)
    Sanford, Fernando; Van Valkenburgh, Peter
  - The chimney in Engineering Grounds: Painting, watercolor, pre-1906, from site of old camp, by Mrs. J.O. Griffin., circa 1900; P308; watercolor on paper; 8.5 x 13 inches (Box A5)
    Gift of Isabel McCracken
    Contents: formerly classes as AM 00-274
    Griffin, Mrs. J. O.
  - Oak tree by bridge: watercolor painting, possible by Louise J. Culver (class of 1896), undated, P309; watercolor on paper; 10.25 x 8 inches (Box A5)
    Given to Archives in 1954
    Contents: formerly classed as AM 00-298
    Culver, Louise Julia, d.1959.
  - Orr, Louis. Stanford University, Eight Etchings: 2 individual ones removed from SUA Museum Collection. Title page and Abside of the Memorial Church, 1930; P049 (Box B2)
    Formerly classed as SUA 00-272 and 00-273
  - Ink drawing of the Law School, when it was still in outer Quad, 1971, P310; ink and wash on paper (Box B5)
    Jennings
  - Old Union building, pencil sketch of one corner, ca. 1930, P311; pencil on paper; 6 x 9 inches (Box A5)
    Original gift of Herbert Hoover; removed from GP collection (old GP9035)
    Lipscomb
  - Watercolor renderings of furnishings for Roble Gym lobby and lounge, 1979; signed J. Pollard. Company was McQuire & Walsh, P312; watercolor; 29 x 20 inches (Box Own box)
    Contents: P312.1 Lobby (round rug); P312.2 Lobby (rectangular rug); P312.3 Lounge
    Roble Gym; J. Pollard
  - Ancestral Registry of Leland Stanford, Jr. compiled by Louise McDanell Browne. Two versions on identical pre-printed form; shows parental couples only, no aunts, uncles, etc., 1906; P313; ink and pencil on paper
    genealogy
  - Ayrshire Farm - 1242 Acres. Residence of Peter Coutts, esq. Mayfield. Santa Clara County, California. [reproduction, negative format, on board], P179; 17.5 x 14 inches (Box B3)
  - Quotes from the Quad 1907-1911 Bruce Bliven. [excerpted from his letters to his family printed on the Improved Albion Press in the Bender Room. ASUL keepsake April 29, 1979], P314; ink on paper; 9.5 x 13 inches (Box A5)
    Transferred to Archives from exhibit staff Nov. 2006
    Bliven, Bruce; Student life.
  - Watercolor sketch of pre-Quake Stanford scene, painted on portion of a postcard; looking down Serra Street past Roble and the Quad. Postcard postmarked 1906., P315; 4.75 x 2 inches (Box A5)
    quad; campus views; unknown
  - In grateful appreciation of service to THE CAMPAIGN FOR STANFORD 1972-1977 [this copy presumably awarded to Lyle McGovern]. Photo of Quad arches (removed from plastic frame)., P316; Printed photo; 9 x 12 inches (Box A5)
    Campaign for Stanford; McGovern, Lyle
  - Encina Hall (front view), chromo-lithograph (anonymous) ca. 1900 [in acid free mount], P317; chromo-lithograph; 7 x 3.5 inches (Box B5)
    Originally purchased by Museum; transferred to SUA 1994
  - Western entrance to Inner Quad, chromo-lithograph (anonymous) ca. 1900 [in acid free mount], P318; chromo-lithograph; 7.25 x 3.75 inches (Box B5)
  - Memorial Church (exterior view), chromo-lithograph, Detroit Photographic Co., ca. 1904 [in acid free mount], P319; chromo-lithograph; 9 x 7 inches (Box B5)
  - Post 1989 Quake images - Proofs for publications ca. 1990, P320 (Box A5)
    Contents: 320.1 carved "ST" possibly fallen to ground; 320.2 sign "DO NOT ENTER Material May Fall From Building"; 320.3 chain link fence in front of west wing of Green Library; 320.4 two fallen urns from front of Quad; 320.5 top of palm tree
  - Toyon Hall, exterior. Color print of a sketch mounted on board., P321; color print; 10 x 8.5 inches (Box A5)
    removed from GP (formerly classed as GP 10771) 12/2007.; Caption or artist name illegible in lower RH corner.
    Toyon Hall; illegible
  - Associated Students Stanford University. This is to Certify that Ralph I. McFadden has been awarded the Stanford Block S in football for the season of '00-'01-'02 [i.e. 1900-1902]. Signed by Paul McCloskey and Arthur E. Worthy, P322; certificate; 9 x 6.75 inches (Box A5)
    stained and discolored
    McFadden, Ralph I.; Athletics
  - To the Resigning Chairman of English [Ian Watt] May 1971. Poem, hand-written; signed below (first names only). Also includes note on presentation of the scroll, [Tom's speech: 5/30/1971], P323; ink on paper board; 17.5 x 24 inches (Box C6)
    Watt, Ian
  - Posters and illustrations [1 item in map case], P273; printed (Box MC)
  - Galopin. Winner of the Derby stakes at Epsom 1875. The Property of Prince Batthyany. [no imprint information] THIS ITEM IS ACTUALLY PART OF MO783, circa 1876; d4fad; colored print; 30 x 23.5 inches (Box MC)
    Horses.
  - Ormonde. Winner of the Derby Stakes at Epsom 1886... The Property of the Duke of Westminster. Imprint: Manchester, John Harrup, 56 Dantzic St. THIS ITEM IS ACTUALLY PART OF MO783, circa 1887; colored print; 31.5 x 25 inches (Box MC)
  - "these from Stanford University gave their lives in the service of their country "[Korea and Vietnam] - copy of the calligraphy sheet done for Memorial Hall prior to completion of the plaque, placed there by Stanford Historical Society, circa 1983; P324; photostatic print; 14 x 17 inches (Box B5)
    Veterans; Korean War; Vietnam War
  - Stanford Memorial Church through the Arches: Lithograph of original watercolor painting, undated; no. 38/995, P325; lithograph; 32 x 26 inches (Box MC)
    Memorial Church; Severin, Charlotte
  - Tresidder, Donald B. Portrait., P326; print; 14 x 11 inches (Box A5)
    Tresidder, Donald B.
  - Christmas cards with Memorial Church images, both with envelopes (originally sent to Pauline Gartzman), 1933; P327 (Box A5)
    Contents: P327.1 Season's Greetings - image inside; P327.2 Stanford Memorial Church image on outside
  - Varian Looks at Radar through the Ages. Series of advertisements with cartoons by C. E. B. Bernard. Text is handwritten but unsure if it's original or printed., circa 1975; P328; printed; 17 x 22 inches (Box C3)
    Bernard, C. E. B.
  - Envelope with images & text re Palo Alto. Images: SU inner quad and University Avenue in PA. Text: Palo Alto seat of Stanford University. 30 miles S. of San Francisco / Population 7000 [and cost of utilities and taxes], P329; printed; 6.5 x 3.75 inches (Box A5)
    From W. Hammon (gift? purchase?) in the 1980s; no accn number noted.
    Palo Alto (Calif.)
  - The Gold Spike. The spike commemorates the joining of the Central Pacific and Union Pacific Railways at Promontory, Utah, on May 10, 1869. Stanford University Museum of Art; Printed by H. S. Crocker co. for the Committee for Art at Stanford; [photo of Gold Spike on red velvet on front, text on back], P330; color print; 6 x 4 inches (Box A5)
    could be a postcard but lacks typical markings on non-image side
    Gold Spike.
  - Untitled [Muybridge spoof featuring Leland Jr. falling off bicylce], 1991; P331; ink on paper, mounted; 9 x 14 inches (Box A5)
    Mark Wilson
  - Stanford [image of Stanford Indian in Cubist style]; signed by Dedini, undated; P332; lithograph; 15 x 23 inches (Box C6)
    Eldon Dedini
  - Stanford [two Indian figures with 1890s student (probably); central Indian figure is holding reproduction of famous portrait of Indians]; signed by Dedini, undated; P333; lithograph; 16.5 x 23 inches (Box C6)
  - Buildings of the Leland Stanford, Jr., University, Palo Alto, Cal. The Inland Architect and News Record Vol. XVII No. 3 [mechanical labs behind quad], circa 1895; P334; printed; 13 x 9.5 inches (Box A5)
    Gift of Wilma Jenkins Hubbard '35, 1982.
  - Buildings on Quadrangle of Leland Stanford, Jr., University, Palo Alto, Cal. The Inland Architect and News Record Vol. XVII No. 3 [Inner Quad view], circa 1895; P335; printed; 13 x 9.5 inches (Box A5)
  - Building of the Leland Stanford, Jr., University, Palo Alto, Cal. The Inland Architect and News Record Vol. XVII No. 3 [Encina Hall], circa 1895; P336; printed; 13 x 9.5 inches (Box A5)
  - The Leland Stanford Junior University, Palo Alto, San Mateo Co. Cal., issued with Christmas Number S. F. News Letter, 1890; P337; 18 x 12 inches (Box B5)
    Copy 1 - Gift of Wilma Jenkins Hubbard '35, 1982. Copy 2 torn and with corner damage.
  - Front view of quad, pre-1905, from either Chemistry or Museum roof. Hand-colored., P338; hand-colored print; 13.5 x 7.5 inches (Box A5)
  - View from front of Post Office showing residential streets. Hand-colored., P339; hand-colored print; 13.5 x 7.5 inches (Box A5)
  - Entrance Gates, second set (pre-1905). Hand-colored., P340; hand-colored print; 13.5 x 7.5 inches (Box A5)
  - View of Quad Corner (Engineering?) (pre-1905). Hand-colored., P341; hand-colored print; 13.5 x 7.5 inches (Box A5)
  - View of East Gates of Quad (pre-1905). Hand-colored., P342; hand-colored print; 13.5 x 7.5 inches (Box A5)
  - Entrance to old Stanford Home and University Grounds, adjoining entrance to Stanford Park, Cal. Specimen print in Sepia Duotone from the press of the Associated Priting Co., San Francisco. [Based on Frank Davey photograph], circa 1895; P343; 12 x 9.5 inches (Box A5)
    Entrance gates (first set); Sphinx
  - Palo Alto, 5353 sired by Electioneer, 125. First Dam: Dame Winnie, Thoroughbred. Owned by Leland Stanford. Palo Alto Stock Farm. Menlo Park, California. [copy 3], P005; lithograph; 18 x 23.5 inches (Box C1)
  - "Home Sweet Home, #I." Depicts "Frossotti Beer Garden," by P.A. Mooney. Print numbered 1 of 30., 1947; ARCH-2016-017; 9 x 12 inches (Box A6)
    Scope and Contents
    Image of Rossotti's, or "Zott's," in Portola Valley. Rossotti's is now known as the Alpine Inn.
    Portola Valley (Calif.) -- Planning.; Student life.
  - Campus scenes by Jim McGuinness. 4 pages from calendar., 1968; ARCH-2016-019; 8 x 10 inches, matted. (Box A6)
    Stanford University -- Campus scenes; Memorial Church
  - Green Library and Hoover Tower by Brian [illegible], 1994; ARCH-2017-099; 11 x 17 inches (Box B2)
  - Artist rendering of unidentified monument, ARCH-2017-134; 11 x 14 inches (mounted on board) (Box C6)
    Text at bottom reads "Scale one inch equals sixteen feet" signed Stanford White
  - Sketch of Herbert Hoover signed "to [Ira Skillick?] with the kind regards of Herbert Hoover" signed by artist [illegible perhaps Charles R. Martin?], 1933; ARCH-2017-136; 7.5 x 10 inches (Box B5)
  - Exterior view of Memorial Church from Inner Quad [framed], ARCH-2017-176; approx. 8 x 11 inches [framed 11.5 x 14.5 inches] (Box 1)
  - "Artistic Homes of California: Country Residence of Senator Leland Stanford, Palo Alto, California.", 1891 Mar 7; Accession ARCH-2017-321 (Box C7)
  - "The Completion of the Pacific Railroad--The Ceremony at Promontory Point, Utah, May 10th, 1869, The Locomotives, Jupiter, of the Central Line, and 119, of the Union Line, Meeting at Junction, After the Driving of the Last Spikes" (Framed), Accession ARCH-2017-322 (Box C7)